# Snigdha Gupta

DIFC, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

□ (+971) 56-917-2890 | snigdhagupta385@gmail.com | sni

## About

I'm a solution driven Scrum Master with 4 years of experience in ITSM for Banking domain. I've led team on Access Management Platform, Incident Resolution and Infrastructure Capacity Planning fostering Agile Principles. I'm CSM® certified and looking to work on products and projects with challenging and interesting problem statement.

# Work Experience \_

### Tata Consultancy Services (for American Express)

Bangalore, India Mar. 2018 - Mar. 2020

#### SCRUM MASTER (PROJECT TEAM LEAD)

- · Organized and facilitated scrum ceremonies daily standups, sprint planning, sprint review, and retrospective to deliver enhancements and new integrations for access management team.
- Ran a Kanban board to handle regular support activities in a first-in-first-out model for high velocity tasks.
- Managed backlog and release planning with product owners to ensure monthly and quarterly release cycles.
- Technically ensure capacity planning for infrastructure by understanding performance of servers in current architecture.
- Technical reviewer for change management on environments to ensure minimal impact of changes on existing system architec-

# Tata Consultancy Services (for American Express)

Bangalore, India

SYSTEM ENGINEER

Mar. 2016 - Mar. 2018

- Development, maintenance and implementation for CA SiteMinder product suite Policy Server, Web Agent and CA Federation. • Configuration of policy servers for upgrades, certification renewal and rotation.
- Integrating applications to OAuth2 flow for several environments (development, quality assurance and production).
- Built proficiency in tools such as Splunk, CA APM, HP sitescope, Oracle Goldengate, Dynatrace to analyse server traffic and incident resolution

# Recognition

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM®), Scrum Alliance **Splunk Fundamental**, Tata Consultancy Services ITIL Service Operation, Tata Consultancy Services

Jan 2021 Jun 2017

Mar 2016

### **AWARDS**

Certificate of Excellence, Lead the team to automate for complex OAuth structure for SSO SiteMinder, using Agile practices

2017

Certificate of Excellence, Traffic and gateway configuration to prevent attacks and vulnerabilities Impact Award, Successful certificate upgrade for federation services in record time

# **Education**

#### PES Institute of Technology (PESIT)

Bangalore, India

**BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN BIOTECHONOLOGY** 

Jun. 2011 - May. 2015

## Skills

Project management, Release Management, Banking, IT Service Management, Authentication and Access **Domains** 

Management, Team and capacity Management

Frameworks Scrum, Kanban, Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), Scrum of Scrums, familiar with LeSS

**Tools** Jira, Confluence, Trello, CA SiteMinder Suite, Splunk, Oracle GoldenGate, SiteScope, DynaTrace

Linux server management, Certificate Patching, Network Load Balancing, Log Analysis and Tracing, Incident Infrastructure

Resolution

English, Hindi Languages

SNIGDHA GUPTA · RÉSUMÉ JUNE 29, 2022